105 Rosecrest Lane: Simpsonville, SC 29680 • (843) 834-1236 • Email: alwaysinnovatingISS@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE:

Experienced educator, having served students in the largest, second largest and fifth largest school districts in the state of South Carolina.

A dedicated leader with a commitment to moving organizations to increased significance and success through clear articulation of vision and meticulous execution.

Intellectual curiosity, academic rigor, scholarly engagement, and commitment to pedagogical excellence, operational precision and service-centered execution.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Southside High School, an International Baccalaureate & AVID School, Greenville, South Carolina *Principal, July 2017 to present*

Clifton Strengths: Focus, Command, Significance, Deliberative, and Learner

- Developed AVID program at school (first in Greenville County Schools) & strengthen the IB curriculum by redesigning the matriculation chart/program of study.
- Provided leadership for all aspects of the instructional program and total operation of the school.
- Responsible for the oversight, visioning and supervision of 111 employees and 870 students from 11 different countries and speak 28 different languages.
- Established ongoing accountability for all students through accelerated learning opportunities, early focus on inquiry based learning and equal access to programs, resources and data for educational advancement of all students.
- Coordinated with stakeholders to establish a new Dual Credit Program (SHS was the last of 14 high schools to implement this program).
- Research, design, and wrote a Grant to fund our AVID program to allow more educational
 opportunities for our first-generation students and create a college learning environment through
 the school.
- Implemented Student-Centered Coaching Model.
- Improve strategies to create a positive school and community culture.

Innovative Strategic Solutions, LLC

Owner & Chief Strategic Consultant, March 2021 to present

- Innovative Strategic Solutions is known as an innovative thought leader in the consulting industry with a strong focus on strategy. Innovative Strategic Solutions will bring the perspective, understanding, and hands-on know-how to build the future as you see it.
- Innovative Strategic Solutions (ISS) strive to provide clients with on-time and top-notch quality consultant services, products, and deliverables.

St. John's High School, Johns Island, South Carolina *Principal, July 2014 – May 2017*

2017 South Carolina Department of Education School Executive Leadership Institute (SELI) 2015 Center for Creative Leadership Coaching Program

- Provided leadership for all aspects of the instructional program and total operation of the school.
- Responsible for the oversight, visioning and supervision of 51 employees and 300 students.
- Established ongoing accountability for all students through accelerated learning opportunities, early focus on inquiry based learning and equal access to programs, resources and data for educational advancement of all students.
- Created the first Charleston area Hospitality and Tourism Career Academy, established school's first Advanced Placement Academy, PLTW Computer Science Career Academy and Culinary Arts Career Academy to provide students with college and or career ready experiences.
- Secured EEDA College and Career Readiness Grant (447,540) for 3 years to implement AVID.

West Ashley High School, Charleston, South Carolina Assistant Principal for Curriculum, July 2013 – July 2014 **2014 South Carolina Assistant Principal of the Year**

- Observed teachers and provided constructive feedback
- Assist principal with the leadership and supervision of all aspects of the instructional programs
- Professional development coordinator
- Advanced Placement Academy administrator
- Test Coordinator and academic textbooks
- Lead Curriculum Administrator

St. John's High School, Johns Island, South Carolina

Associate Principal for Curriculum and Instruction, August 2010 – July 2013

2014 Common Formative Assessment Certification – The Leadership and Learning Center

- Supervised academic and support programs
- Managed School Improvement Grant (SIG) and budget (1.6 million per year for three years)
- Master Scheduler
- Developed a framework for a continuum of services for academic support, interventions, assessment and placement for students to close the behavior and achievement gaps
- Create curriculum mapping for Social Studies and English I

Cane Bay High School, Summerville, South Carolina

Administrative Assistant/Student Intervention Specialist, August 2008 – August 2010

- Coordinated the state testing program
- Chaired the student intervention team to plan interventions for students and monitor progress
- Provided curriculum support to teachers
- Work with teachers to support data usages in the classroom
- Coordinate graduation efforts

James Island Charter High School, James Island, South Carolina

Teacher, August 2003 – August 2008

2006 Wells Fargo Financial Services Teacher of the Year

- Taught S.C. curriculum standards to students in an atmosphere conducive to engaging students using a myriad of instructional modalities
- DECA Advisor and 2007 South Carolina DECA Advisor of the Year

- 2006 National Teacher of the Year (NFTE)
- Teacher Representative for the school charter board
- Developed proposal for Freshmen Academy

EDUCATION:

Doctor of Education – K12 Educational Leadership (Ed.D.), 2020, North Greenville University

Master of Education -Secondary Administration and Supervision (M.Ed.), 2006, Charleston Southern University

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A), 2005, Webster University

Bachelors of Arts (B.A) – Charleston Southern University (2003)

Associate of Science (A.S) – Charleston Southern University (2001)

Certification

72- Secondary Principal74 – Secondary Supervisor

Leadership Activities

Secretary, Greenville Regional Advisory Career Board
South Carolina State Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Deputy Chief of Staff
2019-2021 Vice President of the Charleston Southern University Alumni Association

Vice President Alpha Lambda Sigma Chanter - Phi Reta Sigma Fraternity

Vice President, Alpha Lambda Sigma Chapter – Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity

Greenville County Schools Secondary Academic Advisory Committee member

2017 Charleston 40 under 40 award Winner

2019 Phi Beta Sigma Education Award Recipient

Principal Roundtable Member (High School Representative)

Charleston County School District Allocations Committee Member

Charleston Area Chamber of Commerce Career Academy

2017-2019 Charleston Southern University Alumni Association Secretary and Board of Visitors Member

Committee to redesign strategies for teacher retention and support (GCSD)

Former Member of Charleston Educator Symposium Planning Team

1:1 iPad and Chromebook Implementation administrator (CCSD and GCSD)

Delegation leader for the 2013 Presidential Inauguration

Grant Writer for Charleston County School District Race to the Top and SIG Member of Charleston County School District Common Core Implementation

CCSD and GCSD Professional Development Facilitator

Serve on interview panels for District Level Positions (CCSD and GCSD)

Relevant Training

2020 AVID Administrator

2017 – South Carolina Department of Education Executive Leadership Institute

2016 & 2018 – AVID Trained

2015 & 2016 - AdvancED External Review Team Member

2014 - Harvard Professional Development Trainer

2013 – Certified Trainer for The Leadership and Learning Center: Common Formative Assessments

2013 – South Carolina Department of Education Developing Aspiring Principals

2012 - Marzano Teacher Leadership and Coaching trained

2011 – Charleston County School District Principals for Tomorrow

2012 – SCASA Leadership Academy and SCASA Assistant Principals Webinar

2008, 2012 – SAFE-T and Enhanced ADEPT (TOPS) Evaluator and Mentor trained 2008 – Power School Master Scheduler (BCSD) 2011 – EDGE Academies, The Charleston Education Foundation

Dissertation Title

Educator's Perspectives of Administrative Support and Accountability in High Poverty Schools